ZOE ELLEN POINTON

UX DESIGNER

H: 01344 430 312

M: 07935 408 399

zoepointon123@gmail.com

zoeellenpointon.com

USER RESEARCH SKILLS

Focus Groups

User Journeys

Prototyping

User Testing

Wireframes

Card Sorting

Personas

ANALYTICS SKILLS

Python

D3

Google Analytics

Microsoft Excel

SQL (Basic)

DEV SKILLS

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

DESIGN TOOLS

Adobe CC

Sketch

Invision

Zeplin

AWARDS

UNIVERSITY OF WINCHESTER

Transmedia 2017 Pitch a Project Winner

CERTIFICATIONS

GOOGLE

The Online Marketing
Fundamentals

REFERENCES

TRUDIGITAL

Allan Crabtree

allan@allancrabtree.co.uk

CDG

Sally Hanson

sally@shml.co.uk

An experienced designer with a passion for creating user centred products, based on user research and data insights. Spent the last year studying for a Masters in Design Informatics at the University of Edinburgh. This allowed for skill-set expansion into data driven design and data analytics/visualisation. 2 years experience working within the tech industry as a designer. Looking for a new challenge in user experience design/insight.

EXPERIENCE

JUL 2018 - PRESENT

Freelance Digital Consultant - Maxivation

Freelance work alone side my masters. I worked with various clients; designing customer journeys, creating websites and, writing analytics reports.

APR 2018 - JUL 2018

UX Designer - TruDigital

Formerly part of CDG. Working in a start-up environment allowed me to take more ownership of existing client projects. Creating actionable conversion reports became the greatest part of my role.

MAY 2017 - APR 2018

Junior Designer - CDG

After graduating I joined CDG full-time. My day-to-day role included; running client meetings, user research, wireframes, mock-ups, prototypes, style guides, conversion reporting and user testing. I worked on a variety of client projects that involved designing eCommerce and bookings sites. I also worked with the marketing team creating content for social media campaigns.

As well as working on client projects, I also worked within product teams, creating and refining SaaS mobile applications using agile. Taking part in daily scrum meetings and presenting to stakeholders weekly progress.

MAY 2016 - APR 2017

Digital Design Intern - CDG

During my last year at university I got the opportunity to work alongside my degree as a design intern. This allowed me to develop my design and developer skills in a professional setting.

EDUCATION

SEP 2018 - AUG 2019

University of Edinburgh - MA Design Informatics

Predicted Grade: Merit

SEP 2014 - MAY 2017

University of Winchester - BA Digital Media Design

Grade: First